Finding Aid for Battle Creek Food Company [Miscellaneous printed items] {19--]-1938
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Battle Creek Food Company [Miscellaneous printed items] [19--]-1938
Battle Creek Food Company
0.4 lin. ft.
FB 2 BF686 M678
Miscellaneous printed items of the Battle Creek Food Company mostly relating to health and diet.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Battle Creek Food Company Miscellaneous printed items were received as individual items or as parts of various accessions.
The record group is open without restriction.
Battle Creek, Michigan company formed by John Harvey Kellogg ca. 1906, after his split with his brother Will, to develop and market soy products and health foods.
Miscellaneous printed items of the Battle Creek Food Company mostly relating to health and diet.
Subjects:
Battle Creek Food Company.; Food.; Hygiene.; Medicine--Michigan--Battle Creek.; Public health--United States.
- Miscellaneous printed items
  - The art of slenderizing, [19-], 30 p.; 10 cm. (Box 1)
  - The art of slenderizing the Battle Creek way, [19--], 31 p.; 14 cm. (Box 1)
    (2 copies, slightly different.)
  - Battle Creek selling aids for building business, [1938], 23 p.; 28 cm. (Box 1)
  - Battle Creek special purpose foods, [19--], 23 p.; 18 cm. (Box 1)
  - Colitis: a common and increasing American disease, [19--], 15 p.; 19 cm. (Box 1)
  - Colitis: a common and increasing American disease, [19--], 17 p.; 19 cm. (Box 1)
  - Diet helps for docotors, 1928, 43 p., 2 folded leaves; 23 cm. (Box 1)
  - The ethics of eating flesh, [19--], 18 p.; 15 cm. (Box 1)
  - Foods for high blood pressure, [19--], 12 p.; 16 cm. (Box 1)
  - Foods for slenderizing, [19--], 25 p.; 16 cm. (Box 1)
  - Good eating for health, [19--], 28 p.; 18 cm. (Box 1)
  - Healthful living: fundamental facts about food and feeding, [19--], 47 p.; 23 cm. (Box 1)
  - Healthful living: fundamental facts about food and feeding, [19--], 60 p.; 22 cm. (Box 1)
    (2 copies: identical covers but different text)
  - Healthful living: fundamental facts about food and feeding, [1930 ?], 64 p.; 23 cm. (Box 1)
  - High blood pressure, [19--], 15 p.; 16 cm. (Box 1)
  - Home digest, 1926, 25-28 cm. (Box 1)
    (Issues for May 1927, November 1927, March1933, July 1933)
  - How to eat to build and to maintain good health, [19--], 63 p.; 21 cm. (Box 1)
  - How to eat to build and to maintain good health, ca. 1933, 47 p.; 18 cm. (Box 1)
  - The insulin-dietetic treatment of diabetes, [19--], 12 p., 1 folded leaf; 23 cm (Box 1)
  - The intestinal flora, [19--], 32 p.; 23 cm. (Box 1)
    (2 copies, slightly different)
  - Modern menus and recipes for your health, [19--], 28 p.; 18 cm. (Box 1)
  - The natural method of changing the intestinal flora by causing growth of b. acidophilus without the use of cultures, [19--], 11 p.; 23 cm. (Box 1)
  - Nutritional facts as an aid to healthful living, [19--], 63 p.; 21 cm (Box 1)
  - 100 per cent American blood, [1925 ?], 12 p.; 16 cm. (Box 1)
  - A practical method of changing the intestinal flora, ca. 1932, 16 p.; 22 cm (Box 1)
  - Suggestions for the child's diet, [19--], 14 p.; 16 cm. (Box 1)
  - Tired...sluggish?, [19--], 13 p.; 16 cm. (Box 1)
  - Vitamins, [19--], 22 leaves; 22 cm. (Box 1)
  - What medical authorities say about changing the intestinal flora and worthless commerical cultures, [192-?], 12 p.; 23 cm. (Box 1)
  - What to eat in diabetes, [19--], 40 p.; 16 cm. (Box 1)
  - You will enjoy these modern recipes, [19--], 16 p.; 18 cm. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous flyers, advertisements, and recipes. (Box 1)